Guide to the Tamiment Library Manuscript Files TAM.245
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Gompers, Samuel: Subject File, 1911, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Gordon, David: Paul Robeson and Other Poems (typescript, 47 pp.) Contents: Paul Robeson -- to Nazim Hikmet -- A Letter to Carl -- What "Social" Economics? -- The Legacy -- Let Honesty Guide You -- Collier's Preview of the War They Want -- Where Freedom Lives, Dec 1951 (Box 3, Folder 44A)
- Great Britain: Combination Laws (photocopies, originals in vault), 1749 (Box 3, Folder 45, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Great Britain: Three Broadsides (re: conflict between George IV and his wife Caroline), 1820 (Box 3, Folder 46, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Gronlund, Laurence: Research File (photocopies, notes and outgoing correspondence), 1889-1896 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Hall, Otto: Autobiography (typescript, 12 leave), undated (Box 3, Folder 47a)
  Conditions Governing Access
  As of August 2025, this folder is missing.
- Hall, Robert, 1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 47B)
- Hardie, J. Keir: Correspondence (to Julius Gerber), 1912 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Harvard University Socialist Club: What Harvard Teaches: The Story of Twenty Scrub Women(leaflet), "Welcome to MacDonald" (statement of welcome to Ramsay MacDonald), undated (Box 3, Folder 48a)
- Hayes, Dorsha: Correspondence (Louise Heinze), Oct 13, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Hayes, Frank J.: Correspondence (James Oneal), May 9, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Haymarket Martyrs: Statements, Correspondence, Clippings, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Haymarket Square Riot: Interview with Clarence Darrow (transcript), Correspondence (to H. D. Lloyd), Broadsides (photocopies), 1893-1899 (Box 3, Folder 51a)
- Hebrew Socialist Union (London): Bylaws, 1876 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Henderson, Archibald: Correspondence (Thornton Oakley), Jan 1933 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Herron, Carrie Rand: Subject File, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Hill, Joe (Joseph Hillstrom): Research Correspondence, May 11, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Hillquit, Morris: Correspondence (with Harry Lopatin), Mar 1931 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Hiroshima Commemorative Committee: 10th Annual Commemorative Meeting at Carnegie Hall, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Hohaus, Reinhard A.: "Unemployment Insurance" (typescript, 27 leaves), May 20, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Holly Point Project: Board of Directors Minutes, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Hoover, Herbert: Correspondence to Norman Thomas, Aug 1949 (Box 3, Folder 59a)
- Hoopes, Darlington: Correspondence, Resolution on August Claessens, 1934, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Hourwich, Isaac A.: Lectures (Russian Revolutionary History), 1919 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Hourwich, Isaac A.: Manuscripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Hunt, Lester: Typescript (International Brotherhood of Teamsters), Jan 20, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Iglesias, Santiago: Research Correspondence, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Industrial Union League: Declaration of Principles, Jun, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Industrial Union Party: Statements, 1927-1934 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Institute of International Labor Research, Inc.: Correspondence (Louise Heinze), Feb 28, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Interfaith Movement: Annual Report, Oct 5, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- International Association of Machinists and the Amalgamated Society of Engineers (New York Districts): Minutes, Notes and Reports (re: 8-Hour Movement), 1893-1911 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- International Labor Defense: Constitution, Reports and Resolutions, Dec 29, 1929-Dec 31, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union: Correspondence (Report on Protest Demonstration against the Massacre of our Brothers and Sisters, the Trade Unionists and Socialist Workers of Austria), Feb 16, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union: Enrolled Voters, Bronx County, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union: Training Institute Graduation, Apr 26, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- International Socialist Club: Meeting Notices, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- International Socialist Congress: Autograph Album, "For the Progressive Woman" (includes A. Balabanoff, J. Jaurès, J. Spargo, K. Hardie, C. Despard, etc.), 1910 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- International Socialist Congress: Clippings, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Irish Labour Party and Trade Union Congress: Financial Statements, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Ishill, Joseph: Correspondence (Arthur Leonard Ross), Lists (Libertarian Pamphlets, Periodicals), 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Jaurès, Jean: Manuscripts and Related Correspondence (French language), 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Jewish Socialist Verband: Report of Sales of Dues Stamps, Jun 1951-Sep 1951 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Jews in France: Clippings and Reports (French and German language), 1942 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Jobless-Liberty Party: Correspondence (Austin L. Staley to Nathan Fine), Jul 25, 1932-Jul 26, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Johnpoll, Bernard K.: Correspondence (from Norman Thomas, David Brenner, Ben Josephson, Jervis Anderson, Max Shachtman, Ron Radosh, Israel Solemnick, Frank Zeidler, Oscar Pinkus, William Stern, Darlington Hoopes, Joel Seidman, William A. Maxwell), 1967-1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Johnson, Oakley C. (Committee for Labor and Democratic Biography): Correspondence ("Journey into Tomorrow" tour), Nov 1959 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Josephson, Ben: Correspondence (outgoing), 1928-1962 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Kantorovich, Haim: Correspondence (Earl Browder, Jack Altman), 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Karlin, William: Election Leaflet Drafts, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Kautsky, Benedict: "Lenin's Erbschaft" (typescript, 46 leaves), undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Kautsky, Karl: Correspondence (to Abraham Cahan), Immigration Application Decision, 1933, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Kavesh, Harry: "The Foreign Trade Policy of the U.S.S.R" (typescript, 5 leaves), Feb 2, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Kerensky, Alexander: Letter to Mr. [Afros?], Apr 14, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Knights of Labor: Research Correspondence, Jan 15, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Knitgoods Workers Union: Arbitration Decision vs. Advance Sportswear, Nov 19, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Kobbe, Herman: "Art, Nature and the Child," "Coeducation" (manuscripts), undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Kolehmainen, Mary W.: "The Finnish-Americans in the American Labor Movement" (typescript, 8 leaves), 1981 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Kolombatovich, George: "Through Hell and High Water, or Odyssey of a Balkan Diplomat" (typescript, 242 leaves), undated (Box 4, Folder 27a)
- Koreshan School of Physics: Correspondence (Rand School of Social Science), Aug 10, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Kramer, Samuel P.: "$160,000,000.00" (typescript, 4 leaves), undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Kropotkin, Peter: Three Letters to Mrs. N. F. Dryhurst, Mr. A. R. Dryhurst (photocopies, originals in vault), 1894, 1908, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 29a, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Krupskaya, Nadezhda: Article re: Memoirs (S. Richardson, Associated Press), 1933 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Kruse, William F.: Correspondence (to and from Jay Lovestone, Ben Gitlow, Max Bedacht), 1929 (Box 4, Folder 30a)
- Kuczynski. Jürgen: Correspondence and Manuscripts, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Labor College of Philadelphia: Annual Report, Syllabus for class "Workshop Economics for Textile Workers" by Benjamin W. Barkas, Ph.D., 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Labor Press: Reference List and "Labor Journalism" (typescript, 4 leaves), Jul-57 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Labor's Cooperative Press Association: Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Lafargue, Laura: "Marching On," "Out of Work", undated (Box 4, Folder 34a, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Lamont, Corliss (National Chairman, American Friends of the Soviet Union): Correspondence (to American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky, Layle Lane), 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Laski, Harold J.: Correspondence (incoming and outgoing; including James Oneal), 1936-1946 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Laundry Workers International Union, Local 280: Emergency Appeals, ca.1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Lawrence Defense Conference of New York City: "Befreit Ettor und Giovannitti" (flyer, German language), undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Lawyers Committee on American Relations with Spain: Letter from Charles Rabbins, Secretary, to Maurice Sugar, Jul 14, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Lazarus, Louis: Correspondence (to Louise Heinze re Käthe Kollwitz), Mar 10, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Lazarus, Louis: Unaddressed letter re His Possession of Daniel De Leon's Notebooks, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 40A)
- League for Socialist Education Clubs: Statement re Formation, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Lee, Algernon: Correspondence (David Rubinow), Apr 1930-Dec 1931 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Lenin University (typescript, 21 leaves), undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Lenin, Vladimir Ilyich (aka V. Oulianoff [sic]): Receipt for Payment in Switzerland (photocopy), Sep 13, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Leonard, Cynthia: Research Correspondence, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Lerner, Max: Notes from Lecture (labor and elections), 1938 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Lexington Group: Newsletters, 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Liessen, Abraham: "And the day will arise…" (poem extract), Oct 18, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- London, Jack: Correspondence to Orlando Jay Smith (comment on Smith's book Eternalism: A Theory of Infinite Justice), Aug 4, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- London, Jack: Research Correspondence (Hensley C. Woodbridge), 1962 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Lorwin, Lewis: Correspondence, List of Books and Articles by, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Low, Bela: Correspondence (mostly incoming, including Eugene Debs, Theodore Debs, Algernon Lee, Ludwig Lore, Julius Gerber, A. I. Shiplacoff), 1918-1926 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Lowenfels, Walter: "Letter to the President" (typescript), 1962 (Box 4, Folder 52a)
- Lowenthal, John: Correspondence (regarding cartoons for film U.S.A. vs. Alger Hiss), 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 52b)
- Lynchings: Findings from the Tuskegee Normal and Industrial Institute, Dec 31, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Lynd, Robert S.: Biographical Notes, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Lyons, Eugene: Correspondence (Ted Schapiro, Sidney Hook), 1947, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Lyons, John: Correspondence (George Meany, Samuel Gompers, John L. Lewis, Alfred Robens), "Russia's Land of Promise for the Jews," ( The Christian Register, July 1936), 1915-1956 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- MacDonald, George E.: Obituary Tributes, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 56a)
- MacDonald, James Ramsey: Correspondence to Algernon Lee (photocopies, originals in vault), Aug 1922-Apr 1923 (Box 4, Folder 56b, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Mailly, Bertha: Correspondence (including Morris Hillquit), Financial Records (Camp Tamiment), 1925-1933, 1952, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Maison, Karl Maria: "The Eternal Kindergarden" (typescript, 147 leaves), undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Map: Spain--What Next? (Evening Telegram, Superior, WI), Feb 7, 1939 (Box Shared Tamiment MSOS004, Folder 1)
- Map: Spain (Sunday Worker), undated (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS002, Folder 1)
- Markham, Edwin: Bibliography (Part II, Individual Poems), Correspondence (Benjamin DeCasseres), "Lincoln, Man of the People," "The Comrade World" (Poems), 1912-1953 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Martinez, Rafael A.: Letter (Spanish language), Feb 18, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Matchett, Charles H.: Correspondence, Notes, 1893-1919 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Matthews, J. B.: Correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- Maurer, James H.: Correspondence (outgoing, including Algernon Lee, Karl Kautsky), 1914-1939 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Maurois, Andre: "The Lesson of France" (typescript, 13 leaves), undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Maynard, R. A.: "Debs and Seidel" (lecture transcript), Jun 16, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- McSorley, William J. (General President, Wood, Wire & Metal Lathers International Union): Letter to Anna M. Bourguina, Mar 13, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Meany, George: Clippings, Statement before the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives, Testimony before the Subcommittee on Labor Legislation of the House Committee on Education and Labor., 1955, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Meeropol, Abel (Lewis Allen) and Anne: Sheet music for "Apples, Peaches and Cherries"; Review of "Strange Fruit"; manuscript "In Memory of Anne", circa 1939-1986 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Meyer London Memorial Committee: Correspondence (to Mitchell Loeb), 1962 (Box 4, Folder 67a)
- Meyerson, Ben: "Democracy, Now or Never: An Appeal to Reason" (typescript, 23 leaves), undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Middleton, Owen: "For an Ever Higher Standard of Individual and Collective Work" (typescript, 4 leaves), undated (Box 4, Folder 68a)
- Miller, Marvin D.: Suffolk County District Attorney's Office Press Release, Jul 20, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 68b)
- Milner, Lucille B.: "Big Bill Haywood: The Most Hated Man of All" (typescript, 11 leaves), undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Mindel, Jacob "Pops": Correspondence (from E. J. Dimock, Claudia Jones), 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 69a)
- Minkoff, S. N.: "An Introduction to Socialist Opinion in the United States on the Question of War, 1913-1918" (typescript, 28 leaves), Dec 12, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Mississippi Free Press: Correspondence, Reports and Statements, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- Mollie Maguires: Book Advertisement Circular (photocopy, original in vault), undated (Box 4, Folder 72, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Mooney, Tom: Correspondence (incoming; letter from TM to his mother), 1916-1932, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Mooney, Tom: Court Documents (Affadavits, Petitions), 1917-1918 (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Mooney, Tom: Letter to Stalin; Letter to A.J. Wilde; Photographs; "Crime Scene" drawings, relating to the Preparedness Day bombing, July 22, 1916 in San Francisco., 1930s, undated (Box 4, Folder 74A)
- Morgan, Lewis Henry: 100th Anniversary Commemorative Plaque (photograph), undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
- Morris, Arthur: Clippings, Correspondence (Arthur L. Ross), 1925, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Morris, Richard B.: Lecture on Labor History, pre1861 (typescript, 8 leaves), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Moscow Trials: Untitled Typescript, 14 leaves, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Moyer, Charles H. (President, Western Federation of Miners): Correspondence (to James Oneal), May 16, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Moyer-Haywood Trial: References and Research Correspondence, Jan 1960-Feb 1960 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Mueller, Theodore: "The Socialist Movement in Milwaukee" (typescript, 12 leaves), undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Mutual Society of Journeymen Cabinet Makers, of the City of New-York: Membership Certificate (photocopy, original in vault), 1796 (Box 5, Folder 6a, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Naft, Stephen: "Falangism and Hispanidad in Latin America" (typescript, 62 leaves), undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Nash, Al: Arbitration (Community and Social Agency Employees, Local 1707, AFSCME), Clippings, Correspondence (from Rose Pesotta, Walter P. Reuther), 1944-1961 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Nathan, Otto: Letter to Morris Schappes, Aug 1, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 8A)
- National Education Committee for a New Party: Correspondence (A. Philip Randolph, Israel Feinberg, Pearl L. Willen, Martin Gerber, Sol Levitas, Hiram Elfenbein, Harry W. Laidler, Mary Martinson), Minutes, Reports, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- National Hat Finishers' Trade Association of the U.S.A.: Journeyman's Cards and Books Frauds, Feb 20, 1878 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- National Maritime Union: Arbitration, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- National Maritime Union: Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- National Maritime Union: General, 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- National Maritime Union: Minutes, 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- National Progressive Party: Correspondence (Arthur L. Rosenberg), Elections, 1914-1916 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- National Religion and Labor Foundation: Brochures, Minutes, Reports, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- National Writer's Union: Signed Replies from Marge Piercy, May Sarton, William L. Shirer, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 17A)
- National Women's Trade Union League: Education Program Report, Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1929-1941 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Nearing, Scott: Correspondence (to Samuel Rosenbloom), Jun 8, 1958-Nov 28, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Nearing, Scott: "The American Labor Party" (typescript, 11 leaves), Apr 22, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Nearing, Scott: United States v. Scott Nearing, et. al., Testimony of Scott Nearing (I), Feb 1919 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Nearing, Scott: United States v. Scott Nearing, et. al., Testimony of Scott Nearing (II), Feb 1919 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Neff, Walter: FBI File and FOIA Correspondence, 1942-2000 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Nemiroff, R. B. (Robert): "Harlem Spring Street Song" (typescript, 12 leaves), undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Neuberger, Richard L.: Correspondence (to Sol Stein), Mar 10, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- New World Resettlement Fund: Correspondence, Aug 2, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- New York C.O.R.E.: Untitled Typescript re Elections, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
- New York State Federation of Labor: Correspondence (Thomas A. Murray and Boris I. Nicolaevsky), Mar 1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Nexo, Martin Andersen: Correspondence (to Civil Rights Congress, German language), Jun 8, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- No More War Parade: Suggestions for Participating Organization, Reports of Sub-Committees (typescript, 6 leaves), May 18, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Oak, Liston M.: "Resolution on the San Francisco Conference" (typescript, 3 leaves), "Resolution on International Situation" (typescript, 3 leaves), undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Orthodox People's Union: Flyer for mass meeting with Socialist candidates Morris Hillquit and Jacob Panken, New York City (Yiddish language), Oct 30 [1932] (Box 5, Folder 30a)
- O'Connor, Harvey: Correspondence (to Edward Lewin), 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- O'Hare, Kate: Correspondence, 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Owen, Robert: "Memorial on Behalf of the Working Classes, Addressed to the Allied Powers, Assembled in Congress at Aix-La-Chapelle, by Robert Owen, of New Lanark, in 1818" (manuscript, 27 leaves, English and German language), Sep 20, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Painter's Socialist League: Meeting Announcement Card, Mar 2, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Pan-American Federation of Labor: Correspondence (including Algernon Lee, Rafael Estrella Ureña, William Green), 1920-1930 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Pearson, Beatrice: "The Autobiography of a Communist" (typescript, 81 leaves), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Pearson's Magazine: Correspondence (including Frank Harris, Bruno Guido), 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Pease, Frank (President of the Hollywood Technical Directors Institute): Letter Denouncing All Quiet on the Western Front, May 24, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 37a)
- Pennsylvania Federation of Labor: "Report of Leonard Craig, Director of Workers' Education" (typescript, 8 leaves), Apr 2, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- People's College: Clipping Transcriptions, 1911-1919 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- People's Committee against Hearst: Conference Announcements, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- People's Party of New York: Financial (Expense Reports, Reciepts), 1937-1939 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Perkins, Frances: Correspondence (to John Reynolds), 1912 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Perlman, Selig: Correspondence (to the Conference of Labor Historians), Apr 19, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Perlman, Selig: "Chapter 11: Renewal of the Struggle for Existence" (typescript, 13 leaves), "Chapter 12: Under the Advancing New Deal, 1933-1939" (typescript, 11 leaves), "Chapter 13: 'Defense' and World War II" (typescript, 6 leaves), "Chapter 14, In the Decade After Roosevelt" (typescript, 13 leaves), "Chapter 15: Conclusions and Inferences" (typescript, 12 leaves), 1958 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Pesotta, Rose: Correspondence (incoming and outgoing; Tucker P. Smith, Harry Nilsson, Charlotte Bradley, Amy Hewes, Victor G. Reuther, Jean Carter), Collected Typescripts, 1924-1936 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Petersen, Arnold (Socialist Labor Party): Correspondence (to Louise Heinze), Jun 30, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Petit, Antoine G.: "Castro, Debray versus Marxism-Leninism: Letters to a Venezuelan Friend" (typescript, 184 leaves), 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Philadelphia Tageblatt: Correspondence, 1877-1901 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Philadelphia Tageblatt: Research Correspondence, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Phillips, James Knox: Correspondence, "Underground" (typescript, 4 leaves), "Thirties Red" (typescript, 21 leaves), "Sleuthing Black History: Rediscovering the Quaker-Sponsored Migration of Free Black Farmers to Indiana and Ohio" (typescript, 10 leaves), "Negro-White Integration in a Midwestern Farm Community" (from Negro Heritage), "Negroes in Wisconsin History" (from Negro Heritage), 1970-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Pickens, William: "The Second World Congress against Imperialism" (typescript, 4 leaves), 1929 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Pioneer Youth: "Secretary's Report for First 18 Months of Pioneer Youth" (typescript, 4 leaves), 1924-1925 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Poland: Speeches and Resolution, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 3a)
- Poole, Ernest: Correspondence, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Pouren Defense Conference: Correspondence (Moses Oppenheimer, James Chase), Statements, 1908-1909 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Powderly, Terence V.: Correspondence (typed transcriptions from Letter Press Book), Calling Card, 1887-1924 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Poyntz, Julia Stuart: Letter to Mr. Valentine; Letter from Dudley M. Tucker, Oct 1915 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Pressman, Lee: "Memorandum re: Directive Order Issues by the National War Labor Board in the Basic Steel Case" (typescript, 14 leaves), undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Producers' Exchange of Labour for Labour: Minutes, 1928-1944 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Proletarian Party: Correspondence (Al Wysocki to Rod Speel), Mar 14, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Provincetown Players (program for Brothers and Aria Da Capo), 1919-1920 (Box 6, Folder 10a)
- Provisional Committee for Non-Partisan Labor Defense: Anti-Hearst Mass Meeting, Feb 3 [1934] (Box 6, Folder 10b)
- Pulitzer, Mr..: Letter re: Bust of His Grandfather, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Quintiliano, Luigi: "Le Vergogne Italiane d'America Camorra?, Mafia, Mano Nera" (typescript, 7 leaves, Italian language), 1957, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Rabinowich, I.: Letter to D. J. Struik, Oct 31, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Radulovic, Monty: Tito's Republic, Chapters 1-10 (typescript), 1947 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Radulovic, Monty: Tito's Republic, Chapters 11-24 (typescript), 1947 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Rand School: Correspondence (Algernon Lee, Max Eastman, Ignace Daszynski, 1911-1945 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Rebel Arts: Constitution, "What Is Rebel Arts?" (typescript, 6 leaves), undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Red Flag: List of References on the Red Flag, Its Origin and History (Library of Congress, Division of Bibliography), Oct 2, 1872 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Reed, John: Letter to J.M. Cornell (photocopy), Jan 1919 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Reisman, Samuel: "An Essay on Labor Problems in the United States" (typescript, 58 leaves), Jan 1924 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Reiss, Louis: Correspondence (to Ephraim Fischoff), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Reuther, Walter P.: Letter to Boris Nicolaevsky, Feb 25, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 21a)
- Rich, Jack: Letter to Ben Blaker, Dec 7, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Rifkin, Bernard (Social Democratic Federation): "Resolution on Reconversion, Full Employment and Economic Security" (typescript, 2 leaves), "Resolution on Organizational Activities" (typescript, 3 leaves), undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Riley, Edward H.: Correspondence with Tamiment Library re: William Harrison Riley Research Materia, Karl Marx, etc., 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Robins, Arthur W.: "The National Election" (typescript, 6 leaves), Sep 29, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Robins, Raymond: United States v. Prober, et al. Testimony of Raymond Robins, Oct 18, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 26)